medindia.net 2019-10-19

# Medindia Privacy Policy

Medindia4u.com Pvt. Ltd. ("Medindia", “we”, “us”) operates this website. medindia.net (“Site”), and may operate other websites. Medindia is totally committed to respecting your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our websites. 

### Information We Collect

Medindia collects some non-personally-identifying information of the type that web browsers and servers typically capture, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. Medindia’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how Medindia’s visitors use its website. From time to time, Medindia may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website. 

Medindia also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged in users and for users leaving comments on Medindia.net blogs/sites. Medindia only discloses logged in user and commenter IP addresses under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information as described below, except that commenter IP addresses and email addresses are visible and disclosed to the administrators of the blog/site where the comment was left.

### Google Analytics

Medindia uses Google Analytics to analyze traffic and visitor flow to the website in order to improve the site's content, visitor engagement and site performance. No personal information is collected from Google Analytics. For further information on the privacy policy concerning Google Analytics, please go to <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en>

### Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

Certain visitors to Medindia’s websites may choose to interact with Medindia in ways that require Medindia to gather some personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that Medindia gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who register at Medindia to provide a username and email address, as well as other personal and demographic information on an optional basis, such as name, date of birth, gender. Those who take advantage of some of our advanced features and services, such as creating home pages, or in transactions with Medindia are asked to provide additional information, including as necessary the personal and financial information required to process those transactions. In each case, Medindia collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor's interaction with Medindia. Medindia does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. All visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, and choose to browse the website without registration, with the caveat that it may prevent them from taking advantage of some features available only to registered users. 

### Aggregated Statistics

Medindia may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. Medindia may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, Medindia does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. 

### Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information

Medindia discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on Medindia’s behalf or to provide services available at Medindia’s websites, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using Medindia’s websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. Medindia will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, Medindia discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a subpoena, court order or other governmental request, or when Medindia believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Medindia, third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of a Medindia website and have supplied your email address, Medindia may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what's going on with Medindia and our products. You may also opt-in to receive our newsletters or other periodic communications from us. In all such cases, you have the option to opt-out and unsubscribe from these communications and emails. 

Medindia takes security very seriously and has put in place all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information. 

### Cookies

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor's computer, and that the visitor's browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Medindia uses cookies to help Medindia identify and track visitors, their usage of Medindia’s website, and their website access preferences. Medindia visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using Medindia’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of Medindia’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies. 

### Advertisements

Advertisements appearing on any of our websites may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by Medindia and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

### Privacy Policy Changes

Medindia may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Medindia’s sole discretion. Medindia encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change. 

### Legitimate Interest

Exponential Interactive, Inc, as our partner, have a legitimate interest to collect and profile personal data in the form of IP address and cookie ID from users on our website in order to provide targeted online advertising and ad measurement. For more details including opt-out requests, access requests or complaints, please review their [privacy policy](http://exponential.com/privacy/) or contact their data protection officer via [privacy@exponential.com](mailto:privacy@exponential.com).

### Contact Us

If you have comments or questions about our privacy policy, you can complete a  [User Feedback Form,](http://www.medindia.net/feedback.asp) send an email to [info@medindia.net](mailto:info@medindia.net) or write to us at the following address:

Medindia4u.com Pvt. Ltd.  
A-113, 3rd Avenue,   
Anna Nagar,  
Chennai-600102, India  
Phone : +91-44-42612731

Last updated on: May 12, 2016
